noceilings.org 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Clinton Foundation

##### Effective: August 27, 2018

The Bill, Hillary & Chelsea Clinton Foundation (the “Foundation”) is committed to the lawful and transparent collection and use of personal information. This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) explains what information we collect and why we collect it, how we use that information, and your options for controlling and updating your information.

By using our websites[1] (the “Sites”), you agree to be legally bound by this Policy and the [Terms of Use](https://www.clintonfoundation.org/terms-use), as they may be amended from time to time. If you do not agree to this Policy or cannot form a legally binding contract, you may not use the Sites.

If at any time you have questions about this Policy, please let us know by contacting us at [development@clintonfoundation.org](mailto:development@clintonfoundation.org).

##### Information Collected

We collect two types of information from you: (1) personally identifying information voluntarily provided by you (“Personally Identifying Information” or “PII”), and (2) non-identifying data about your use of our Sites (“General Information”).

We collect information in the following ways:

 **Personally Identifying Information (PII)**

Personally Identifying Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, phone number, credit or debit card information, bank information, job application information, resumes and cover letters. The Foundation collects PII when you make a donation, whether online or through another means, and when you voluntarily submit such information, such as by filling out a job application, signing up for an email distribution list, or purchasing merchandise on one of our Sites. 

It is your choice to provide PII. You do not need to disclose more PII than is requested.

You should not provide PII about others unless you are expressly authorized to do so.

We may receive PII about you from other sources, including your company/organization, professional references, publicly-available sources, third-party analytics providers, and other third parties. For example, we may receive your PII if: someone at your company/organization designates you as a contact person for that company/organization or includes information about you in proposal documents; another visitor includes it in any feedback, comments, photos, videos, or other information submitted via online portals, electronic forms, surveys, or interactive portions of our sites; or one of our employees or service providers  or a third party acting on apparent authority provides it to us when registering you to access our facilities or our sites, apply for a job, or participate in one of our events.

 **General Information**

The Foundation automatically collects General Information about which of our Sites you visit and how you navigate them. General Information may include, without limitation, your:

  * Session date and time
  * Internet Protocol (IP) address
  * Internet Service Provider (ISP)
  * Location
  * Language
  * Browser, operating system and device types
  * Source or referral sites; and
  * Browsing behavior, including pages visited, hyperlinks clicked, session times and search requests.

General Information is collected using tracking technology, including cookies and web beacons. The information collected via cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies is anonymous and not personally identifiable. Please note that we use these technologies across our Sites and social media platforms.

Cookies allow the Foundation to measure activity on the Sites and to improve your user experience by, for example, remembering your passwords and viewing preferences and allowing you to visit any member-only parts of the Sites without re-registering.  If you do not want us to collect information using cookies, you can disable this function in your browser. If you block cookies from us, however, you may not be able to see personalized content and our website may not function optimally.

The Foundation may use electronic images known as web beacons to monitor activity on our Sites, as well as across social media platforms and other websites. These web beacons allow the Foundation to provide personalized services and advertising content to our viewers.

##### How We Use Your Information

We aggregate and analyze General Information and use it for operational and administrative purposes, including to identify our Site visitors’ levels and areas of interest in our content, and to improve the Sites. We may also share with third parties aggregated or anonymized General Information that does not directly identify you.

We use PII for the purposes for which it was collected, and for the limited purposes set forth below.

We do not share, transfer, exchange or disclose PII with third parties, **except** :

  * To support the Foundation’s mission. Specifically, we may share your information with our employees, agents, subsidiaries and affiliated entities, and certain third parties, such as contractors and service providers that need access to such information to carry out work on our behalf, including to:
    * respond to your requests,
    * process donations or merchandise orders,
    * send newsletters, surveys, notices or content, and
    * administer, enhance and troubleshoot the Sites;
  * To change website hosts or when our host transfers business assets (as described below);
  * As required by law, court order, subpoena or legal process; or
  * To comply with the Foundation’s donor disclosure obligations

The Foundation may also exchange, or authorize the exchange of, PII for a third party’s fundraising or marketing purposes, unless you opt out of such exchanges as provided for by this Policy.

The Foundation does not sell PII for a third party’s fundraising or marketing purposes.

##### Your Right to Control Your Personally Identifying Information

If you prefer that the Foundation not share your PII with third parties as described above, please email us at [development@clintonfoundation.org](mailto:development@clintonfoundation.org).

You may change or remove PII previously provided to us through the Sites by emailing [development@clintonfoundation.org](mailto:development@clintonfoundation.org). If you signed up for, but no longer wish to receive, Foundation emails, you may remove yourself from our distribution lists by sending us an email through our [Contact Page](https://www.clintonfoundation.org/about/contact-us), or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link that is at the bottom of every email from the Foundation.

##### Donor Disclosure

Consistent with our commitment to transparency, we disclose our donors, listed by range of donation amount. View the donors list [here](https://www.clintonfoundation.org/contributors).

##### Transfer of Business Assets

At any time, this Sites’ web host may be acquired, merge with another organization or acquire or buy other businesses or assets. In such transactions, General and Personally Identifying Information may be among the transferred assets.

##### Our Commitment to Data Security

PII is stored on the servers of certain third-party service providers.  Such service providers are required to use best practices to maintain the confidentiality of your PII, consistent with this Policy. Additionally, service providers may only use your PII for the purpose of providing services to us.  Sensitive data such as credit card numbers are encrypted and tokenized using SSL and other industry standard measures to provide an additional level of security.

The transmission of information via the Internet can never be completely secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted to our sites and any such transmission is at your own risk.

We take steps to protect the safety of your PII. The Sites have security measures in place to help protect loss, misuse, or alteration of such information under our control. However, we cannot guarantee the security of your General or Personally Identifying Information, and we do not assume any liability for third party use of your General or Personally Identifying Information, whether obtained legally or illegally from or through our Sites.

##### Links

Our Sites may contain links to third-party websites. This Policy does not apply to any third-party websites. The Foundation is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any third-party websites.  We encourage you to review the privacy and other online policies of other websites that you link to, visit, and/or use.

##### Children

The Sites do not seek to collect any information from children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect PII from children. If you become aware of any PII we have collected from a child, please contact us at [development@clintonfoundation.org](mailto:development@clintonfoundation.org). If we learn that we have collected PII from a child, we will take steps to delete the data without notice as soon as possible.

##### Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Foundation may update this Policy at any time.  Any changes to the Policy will be reflected on this “Privacy Policy” page, and by continuing to use the Sites, you agree to those changes.  We may also notify you about significant changes in the way we treat Personal Information via email or placing a prominent notice on our Sites.

##### Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please email [legal@clintonfoundation.org](mailto:legal@clintonfoundation.org) or send us a message through our Contact Page. You may also contact us via mail at: Clinton Foundation, 1200 President Clinton Avenue, Little Rock, Arkansas 72201.

YOUR USE OF THE SITES SIGNIFIES YOUR AGREEMENT TO THE TERMS OF USE, INCLUDING THIS PRIVACY POLICY.
